# Iegor Riepin

I am a postdoctoral researcher at the <u>ENSYS @ TU</u> Berlin

My research stands at the intersection of economics and operations research. The overarching goal is to provide empirical and computational evidence to guide publicand private sector stakeholders in dealing with challenges of energy transition. Generally, I enjoy using mathematical models to compute some stuff. I believe in open science, and I try to contribute by sharing my code, data and teaching materials.



Personal page: <u>iriepin.com/</u>

LinkedIn: <a href="mailto:linkedIn:com/in/iegor-riepin/">linkedIn: linkedin.com/in/iegor-riepin/</a>

E: <u>iegor.riepin@tu-berlin.de</u> | <u>iegor.riepin@gmail.com</u>

### Work experience

 $2022.03 \quad \quad - \quad \textbf{Postdoctoral researcher} \mid \textbf{Energy system modeler}$ 

present Department of Energy Systems <u>ENSYS @ TU Berlin</u>

Open-source energy system modeling: <a href="https://pypsa.org/">https://pypsa.org/</a>

I work on the <u>24/7 Carbon-Free Energy by 2030</u> project funded by Google. In October 2022, we published <u>the first study</u>. The work on this project is open and reproducible: <u>https://github.com/PyPSA/247-cfe</u>

2014.11 - Research fellow | PhD student

2022.02 **ESM group lead (**2021.09 – 2022.02)

Brandenburg University of Technology (BTU CS), Germany

Chair of Energy Economics

I have carried out independent and third-party funded research on energy economics & energy systems modeling. The topics included infrastructure investments, decisions under uncertainty, risk-aversion, sector coupling and energy auctions.

2019.09 – Visiting researcher

2019.10 University of Victoria, Canada | Institute for Integrated Energy Systems

My work was focused on robust optimization algorithms applied to

electricity system expansion problems.

2013.10 – Student assistant

2014.09 Chair of Energy Economics, BTU CS

2013.09 – **Intern**2013.10 DIW Berlin, Institute for Economic Research, Germany

Department: Energy, Transportation, Environment

#### Academic background

2014.11 -	PhD (summa cum laude) in energy economics
2022.06	Supervision: Prof. Felix Müsgens   BTU CS
	PhD thesis 'Modeling challenges of modern energy markets: studies on uncertainty, complexity, and constant change' is published in open access.
2012 - 2014	M.Sc. (Hon) in Power Engineering BTU CS, Germany   Final grade: 1.2 (/1)
2008 - 2012	B.Sc. (Hon) in Heat Power Engineering ZSEA, Ukraine   Final grade: 4.98 (/5)

## Third-party projects

2022.03	@TUB: 24/7 Carbon-Free Energy Procurement. Funding: Google Inc.
present	See Operating on 24/7 Carbon Free Energy by 2030 objective by
	Google.
2021	@BTU: TransHyDE: System analysis of transport solutions for green
(ongoing)	hydrogen. Funding: BMBF (Federal Ministry of Education and Research)
, ,	Cooperation: >30 partners   <u>Project web page</u>
2017	@BTU: Design of auctions for market premia for onshore wind
	generation: theoretical and experimental testing. Cooperation:
	CERGE-EI. Summary
2016	@BTU: Strategy 2020: modelling of forward prices for natural gas
	in European gas markets. Funding: industry partner. Cooperation: <u>r2b</u>
	energy consulting GmbH
2014 - 2016	@BTU: Fundamental gas market analysis in a context of the
	German energy transition process. Funding: gas trading utility.
	Cooperation: <u>r2b energy consulting GmbH</u> . <u>Summary</u>

### Peer-reviewed journal articles

1. Energy Economics (2023). Risk aversion and flexibility options in electricity markets

Möbius, T., Riepin, I., Müsgens, F., van der Weijde A. H.

DOI: <u>doi.org/10.1016/j.eneco.2023.106767</u> <u>Working paper at arXiv (2021) | Code</u>

2. Working paper. Hourly versus annually matched renewable supply for electrolytic hydrogen

Zeyen, E., Riepin, I., Brown, T.

Working paper DOI:  $\underline{\text{doi.org}/10.5281/\text{zenodo.7457441}} \mid \underline{\text{Code}}$ 

3. Applied Energy (2022). Adaptive robust optimization for European strategic gas infrastructure planning

Riepin, I., Schmidt, M., Baringo, L., Müsgens, F.,

DOI: doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2022.119686 | Code

Working paper at Optimization Online (2021)

4. Energy Policy (2022). Policy choices and outcomes for the global competitive procurement of offshore wind

Jansen, M., Beiter, P., Riepin, I., Müsgens, F. Juarez Guajardo-Fajardo, V., Staffell, I., Bulder, B., Kitzing, L.

DOI: <u>10.1016/j.enpol.2022.113000</u> | <u>Data</u>

Working paper at arXiv (2022)

5. Applied Energy (2021). Modelling uncertainty in coupled electricity and gas systems—Is it worth the effort?

Riepin, I., Möbius, T., Müsgens, F.

DOI: 10.1016/j.apenergy.2020.116363 | Code

Working paper at arXiv (2020): arxiv.org/abs/2008.07221

6. Nature Energy (2020). Offshore wind competitiveness in mature markets without subsidy.

Jansen, M., Staffell, I., Kitzing, L., Quoilin, S., Wiggelinkhuizen, E., Bulder, B., Riepin, I., Müsgens, F.

DOI: <u>10.1038/s41560-020-0661-2</u> | <u>Code</u> | <u>Supplementary data</u>

Nature Energy News & Views | Media coverage: 118 news stories from 116 outlets

7. The Energy Journal (2022). Seasonal flexibility in the European natural gas market.

Riepin, I., Müsgens, F.

DOI: 10.5547/01956574.43.1.irie | Code

Cambridge Working Papers in Economics (2019)

DOI: 10.17863/CAM.43923 | Abstract | Non-Technical Summary | PDF

## (Mostly peer-reviewed) Conference papers

8. IEEE EEM (2022). Modeling of Extreme Weather Events—Towards Resilient Transmission Expansion Planning.

Bernecker, M., Riepin, I., Müsgens, F.

DOI: <u>10.1109/EEM54602.2022.9921145</u>

9. IEEE EEM (2020). Regret analysis of investment decisions under uncertainty in an integrated energy system.

Möbius, T., Riepin, I.

DOI: 10.1109/EEM49802.2020.9221935

10. IEEE EEM (2018). Integrated electricity and gas market modeling – effects of gas demand uncertainty.

Riepin, I., Möbius, T., Müsgens, F.

DOI: <u>10.1109/EEM.2018.8469790</u> | <u>preprint version</u> | <u>Video</u>

11. IEEE EEM (2018). Is offshore already competitive? Analyzing German offshore wind auctions.

Müsgens, F., Riepin, I.

DOI: <u>10.1109/EEM.2018.8469851</u> | <u>preprint version</u> | <u>Video</u>

12. IEEE EEM (2016). Modelling of world LNG market development: focus on US investments and supplies.

Montenegro, R., Riepin, I., Hauser, P.

DOI: <u>10.1109/EEM.2016.7521361</u>

13. ZSEA (2011). Usage of solar energy for heating service and domestic water heating.

Riepin, I. | VII all-Ukrainian scientific conference. Vol. 2, pp. 78 - 83.

14. ZSEA (2011). Ukrainian market prospects in the field of alternative energy sources.

Riepin, I. | The annual conference for graduate students. pp. 186 - 192.

#### Science explainers, media, project reports

15. Project study (2022). System-level impacts of 24/7 carbon-free electricity procurement in Europe.

Riepin, I. and Brown, T.

Zenodo

16. SSRN (2021). Grok it and use it: Teaching energy systems modeling

Riepin, I., Sgarciu, S., Bernecker, M., Möbius, T., Müsgens, F.

DOI: dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4320978 | Course GitHub

17. CarbonBrief (2020). The era of 'negative-subsidy' offshore wind power has almost arrived

Riepin, I., Jansen, M., Staffell, I., Müsgens, F.

Guest post

18. e|m|w.trends (2020). Offshore-Windenergie - subventionsfrei?

Müsgens, F. and Riepin, I.

Guest post

19. Oxford Institute for Energy Studies & BTU CS (2015). A note on climate policy negotiations at the threshold of COP-21 in Paris.

Müsgens, F., Poudineh, R., Riepin, I.

PDF

#### Some public talks

1. Navigating to a greener Europe with 24/7 hourly clean electricity procurement

PDF | Code @ Enerday, Dresden 2023

- 2. 24/7 A new paradigm for power procurement?
  - PDF | Code @ European Climate and Energy Modelling Platform 2022
- 3. European Natural Gas Infrastructure Expansion Planning: An Adaptive Robust Optimization Approach
  - PDF | Code @ EWI Cologne & BTU CS Research seminars 2021
  - PDF | Code @ European Conference on Operational Research, Athens, 2021
- 4. The costs of ignoring uncertainty and the value of perfect information: a toy model.
  - PDF | Code @ Doctoral seminar, BTU CS, 2019
- 5. Robust optimization of electricity system expansion.
  - PDF | Code @ University of Victoria, Canada, 2019
- 6. Economic impacts of uncertainty in integrated electricity and gas markets.
  - PDF @ 30<sup>th</sup> European Conference on Operational Research, Dublin, Ireland, 2019
- 7. Integrated electricity and gas market modelling effects of gas demand uncertainty.
  - PDF @ EEM2018 Conference, Lodz, Poland, 2018
  - PDF @ PhD seminar Cottbus-Leipzig-Dresden, 2018
- 8. Integration of electricity and gas market models.
  - PDF @ Energy modelling seminar, IER, Universität Stuttgart, 2018
- 9. Application of non-linear and complementarity problems for natural gas market modelling.
  - PDF @ Research seminar with chair of Mathematical Economics, BTU CS, 2017
  - PDF @ Internal research seminar, BTU CS, 2016
- 10. Natural Gas Storages in Competition with Alternative Flexibility Sources.
  - PDF @ 39<sup>th</sup> IAEE International Conference, Bergen, Norway, 2016
  - PDF @ PhD seminar Cottbus-Leipzig-Dresden, 2016
- 11. Prospects for Shale Gas Exploration in Europe: Ongoing Experience.
  - PDF @ 38<sup>th</sup> IAEE International Conference, Antalya, Turkey, 2015

### Teaching experience

2014 - present	Supervision of master's and bachelor's theses, and study projects in energy economics and all around modeling of energy systems.
WS17/18 WS18/19 WS19/20	Energy Systems Modeling (course development, selected lectures, tutorials, supervision of student projects)  Lecture: Prof. Dr. Felix Müsgens   Course GitHub page
From WS14/15 until SS2018	Power System Economics 1 (Winter terms   tutorials)  Power System Economics 2 (Summer terms   tutorials)  Lecture: Prof. Dr. Felix Müsgens and Prof. Dr. Stefan Zundel

# Scholarships & awards

2017 - 2019	Postgraduate scholarship, BTU CS (Promotionsstipendium des Landes Brandenburg, GradV)
2014	Rheinstahl foundation study scholarship (Master degree)
2013	STIBET study scholarship, DAAD (Master degree)
2010	Zaporizhia city administration scholarship (Bachelor degree)

# Some technical skills and languages

Mathematical	GAMS (project-related use, independent research and teaching)
modeling &	Python (project-related use, independent research and hobby
programming	projects)
	Git (version control)
Languages	English (fluent)
	German (C1 certificate)
	Ukrainian (native fluent)
	Russian (native fluent)

## Follow the stars

https://iriepin.com/post/

Berlin, July 2023